ROMAN UKRAINA

Phone: +375 25 7785765

Email: qa.romanukraina@gmail.com

Skype: Roman Ukraina

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/roman-ukraina/



Objective

SOFTWARE TESTING SPECIALIST

Summary

A highly motivated and skilled individual is searching for a position of a Software QA Engineer. Passed "Software functional testing" specialized course by IT Academy. Have strong positive attitude to learning new tools and technologies. Excellent analytical and problem-solving skills are among my pluses.

I possess such soft skills as:

- educability (constantly improving my skills, also have already watched Rusov's course "QA engineer from Zero" and now am reading "Software testing" by Kuliikov)
- huge wiling to develop in this sphere and to reach something worth
- cooperation with other team members (but not only at work, have a plenty of interests and hobbies to discuss during free time)
- although, the ability to find problem solutions alone, without disturbing anyone
- diligence and attention to details, as these are the key elements of the whole industry

Hard Skills

- good knowledge of English (C1+), also possess English ICAO level 4 certificate, Polish (Beginner), Ukrainian (native), Russian (native)
- knowledge of SDLC
- knowledge of methodologies (Waterfall, Agile Scrum/Kanban);
- making testing documentation (checklists, test cases, bug reports, TRR)
- types of software testing
- test design technics: Equivalence Partitioning/Boundary Value Analysis, pairwise testing (PICT), Cause/effect;
- using specialized means (JIRA, TestRail, Postman, Katalon, DevTools, Android Studio, JMeter)
- knowledge of SQL
- basic knowledge of HTML, CSS, JSON, XML

Work Experience

August 2022 – nowadays – B2B Support Manager (Game Aggregator), SOFTSWISS, remote

During work I use such means as Kibana (analyzing requests and responses), JIRA (tickets solving), Confluence.

April 2022 – August 2022 – Operational and client communication specialist, Star Call Center, Minsk

April 2022 - June 2022 - IT-Academy, Trainee

Was a member of the team on the real project "Tango.me", tested desktop web version of the application. For different modules, I prepared a checklist, test cases based on it, made a test run and reported bugs in JIRA. Also prepared TRR. During this project I learned to collaborate with a team, how to make understandable test documentation and to ask correct questions, when it is necessary to clarify the requirement.

October 2013 – April 2022 – Air Traffic Controller, BelAeroNavigatsia, Gomel Main responsibilities:

- communication with pilots using both general and aviation English
- high workload during controlling the aircraft movement in the air and on the ground
- · collaborating with my team and adjacent sectors

Achievements:

- Best Air Traffic Controller Competition (4th place, victory in a single nomination)
- Football Competition among Belarussian Air Traffic Controllers (1st place)
- Was given a Gratitude for flights safety

Education

April – June 2022 – Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy), Trainee

Course: "Software functional testing"

Course description
My certificate

May 2016 - General and Aviation English course, Bournemouth, UK

September 2008 – June 2013 – State Flight Academy of Ukraine Specialization: **Air Traffic Controller**